So friends, if your vehicle's insurance
paper or policy document is lost or
torn, then this video is for you.
In this video, I am going to show you the complete and live process of downloading the
original policy document
or insurance document of any vehicle just by using the vehicle number.
For this, you will not need any engine number
or chassis number. You just
need to have your vehicle number.
So let's start. For this, you have to
open any browser in your mobile,
go to the search bar and here you will
type 'know your vehicle details'.
After writing this, you have to search, then
you will click on the first link that comes up,
then the Citizen login
page will appear in front of you. If you
give an email ID, give this verification
code below and click on generate OTP.
Then an OTP will be sent to your mobile number and email ID. By
giving that OTP here, click on verify.
After verifying the OTP, you will give your name here,
then create a strong password and
confirm the same password again below.
You will see a sample of the password here.
Similarly, you have to create a strong
password, then click on save,
then a message of thank you will come, Citizen
user has been cut successfully, your account has been
created here, now
click on back to vehicle search here, again you will
come to the login page, now here you will
give the same mobile number with which
you had created the account here, then after
giving this verification code you will click on next,
here you will enter the same password
which you had just created, then
click on continue, again
OTP will be sent to your mobile number, after giving OTP here you will
click on verify, as soon as you login, a
page like this will come in front of you, here
you will see the option of enter vehicle number under RC status,
here you have to
give the number of the vehicle for which you
want to download the insurance document,
after that you will enter this captcha code below,
after doing this you have to
click on vehicle search below, as soon as you search, the
complete details of your vehicle will appear in front of you,
here the name of the vehicle, owner name,
registration date will be written in validity  You
can check how long your vehicle's
pollution certificate is valid,
how long is the validity date of MV tax, fitness, and registration.
You
can see all this here. Below, you'll see insurance
details written. This part is
important. Here, you'll be told
which insurance company you've insured your vehicle with, and
what the policy number is.
You'll also see this policy number written,
and the date for when that policy is valid. So, simply
remember the name of the insurance company
and copy or screenshot the policy number. So, let's
copy the policy number here.
After doing this, you'll close this page.
After doing this, you'll have to
go to the Play Store and
install the Deez Locker app. If you already have the
Locker app installed on your phone, you'll need to
update it from the Play Store. So, let's
install it.
After installing it, you'll open it. Here, you'll
select your language.  You will
click on continue. Here you are being
told about LOR. LOR
is such an app where you
can keep all your documents securely saved
and you can use it at any place.
So here you have to click on Let's Go,
then click on Get Started.
If you
already have an account in LOR, then by clicking on Sign In here,
you will
log in to the account with your mobile number. And if you have
come here for the first time and the account is
not created, then you have to click on Create Account. Then you will
give your full name here. Keep in mind that here you have to
write your full name with the same spelling
as the name is written on your Aadhar card. Then
here you will click on Date of Birth and from
here you will select your date of birth. You have to
select the same date of birth
as the date of birth is written on your Aadhar card.
Then from here you will select gender.
In Mobile Number, you will give your mobile number and
an email ID. Then here you will
set a six-digit security PIN.
After giving all the details, below you
Click on Sub, then an OTP will be sent to this number.
Enter the OTP here.
Here you are being asked to verify your Aadhaar number.
However, you
can verify the Aadhaar number later. If
you want to verify later, then
click on Skip for Now below. If
you want to verify now, then
you have to give your Aadhaar card number here. Then
click on Next. Then the
OTP will be sent to the mobile number linked to your Aadhaar card.
Enter the OTP here. Click on Submit.
Your account has been created in the locker. Now
click on Sign In here. Here
you will give the same mobile number with which
you had created the account, then click on Next.
If you have created two Digi Locker accounts with this number, then the
name of both the accounts will appear here. You will select your account.
Then here you will
enter the same security PIN which
you had created just now. Then click on Sign In.
OTP will be sent to your mobile number and email. You will give the OTP here. Click on Submit.
Here you will be asked for permission.
All the permissions will be granted. As soon as you
log in to the locker,  A similar page will appear.
Below you will see four tabs: Home, Search, Issue, and
Menu. Here, you
need to click on the Search tab. Click on Search for Document above.
Here, you need to
type the name of the insurance company
that you just found. For example,
if SBI was written in the Insurance Company section, then
you need to type SBI here. As soon as you
type SBI, you will see the
option to download SBI's car policy and two-wheeler policy.
If ADFC was written there, then
type ADAC here. You
can see below that the option to download car and two-wheeler
insurance copies has appeared.
Similarly,
you need to type whatever was written there. If it was Ekko, then
type ACKO here. Here
you can see that if you want, you can download Ekko's
car or two-wheeler insurance copy
from here. If you face any
problem in searching the name of the insurance company, then all you need to do is
come back and come down to the Search tab.
Scroll down and you will
see the category.  You will
see the category of Banking and Financial, click on
it, as soon as you click, a
list of all the insurance companies will appear in front of you,
here you can
download their policy document in PDF,
here you will
see the list of all the insurance companies of India, if you keep
scrolling down, you will get the complete list here, here
you will
see the name of the insurance company and its logo, you can easily identify the insurance company
here, for example, if
your insurance company was of Ekko, then
click on Ekko, here it will ask you whether
you want to download the insurance copy of the car
or two wheeler, if you
want to download the two wheeler, then
click on Two Wheeler, here your name will be
automatically taken from your Aadhar card
in the policy number, here you will
copy paste the same policy number which
you had just searched and copied,
then give your mobile number,
click on Get Document, wait for a few seconds,
your insurance policy is getting fetched,
see, the original
insurance policy document of my car has been downloaded,
two wheeler insurance policy, simply
you have to click on this, it is
absolutely  This is the original document,
you can use it anywhere. If
you want, you
can also share it directly from here with anyone. You will find the share button below,
you will click on it and you can share
it from here wherever you want to share it.
If you
want to download it on your mobile, you will find the
download button here, you will click on it.
This policy paper will be
downloaded in PDF format on your mobile. So we have saved
our vehicle's policy document on our
mobile. See,
this is a total of 10 pages policy document of my vehicle.
So I hope you liked the video. If you
liked the video, then like this video and
share it with your friends.
And if you have come to the channel for the first time, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell icon.
And if you
want to avail any similar online service from us sitting at home, then
you can call on this number.